

Tanishq Biswas

UI/UX Designer and Developer

Looking for a challenging career that demands and enhances the best of my professional ability in terms of technical, designing & analytical skills. To be able to add value to the organization with my quick learning skills, problem-solving skills, and developing UI/UX with responsive design principles.

tanishqbiswas@gmail.com

+91-8463890200

in linkedin.com/in/tanishqbiswas



github.com/tanishqbiswas

EDUCATION

B.Tech (Computer Science and Engineering)

Lovely Professional University, Punjab 07/2019 - Present

CGPA 7.82

Diploma (Computer Science and Engineering)

Lovely Professional University, Punjab

07/2017 - 05/2019 CGPA 9 18

Intermediate

Bharat Mata Convent Sr. Sec. School, MP

06/2016 - 05/2017 Percentage 60%

Matriculation

Bharat Mata Convent Sr. Sec. School, MP

07/2014 - 05/2015 CGPA 7.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer

BigoBrain Technology

03/2021 - 04/2021

Designed the UI and created prototype of the project according to their requirements.

Digital Marketing Intern and UI Designer Career Shuttle

07/2020 - 12/2020 Kolkata, India

Working on creative banners and designs, creating social media Campaigns, maintaining website, SEO and Designing their website on Wix.

Graphic Designer Freelance

06/2018 - 12/2020

Worked with 15+ Organization and Companies for designing various creatives as per

HIGHLIGHTS

Organizer of North India's biggest fest Youthvibe.

Core Member

Head of E-Campaigning cell at Department of Youth Capital, LPU.

Core Member

Successfully managed 20+ Events over a span of 3 years in Lovely Professional University.

Organizer

Took part in Guinness World Record for 'Largest Bhangra'.

Participation

Volunteer in Indian Science Congress.

Volunteer

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Portfolio App

A Portfolio app for developer/designers built with React JS. Use it to showcase your work, experience and other information to clients

Weather App

 The project is developed using React JS. Here we can find the temperature of any city around the globe. This project works on real time data by fetching information from an API

Recipe App

The project is developed using React JS. Tells the recipe of any cuisine, developed in React JS

Infinity Runner Game

The project is developed on Unity 3D using C# as a backend language. This game has a character which run infinitely which need to collect coins and dodge the obstacles.

CERTIFICATES

Fundamentals of Digital Marketing (Google)

04-2021 - 04/2021

Interactivity with JavaScript

09/2020 - 09/2020

Data Structure and Algorithms (GeeksForGeeks)

06/2020 - 07/2020

HTML, CSS & Java Script for Web Developer

04/2020 - 05/2020

LANGUAGES

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Bengali

Native or Bilingual Proficiency